Last update : 01/2021



FIRAT GÜRSOY SOFTWARE SPECIALIST

E-Mail: firatgursoy@gmail.com

Phone: +90-553-158-85-80

Linkedin : linkedin.com/in/firatgursoy

GitHub : github.com/firatgursoy

Hi! I'm a computer engineer and science addict from Turkey. I have been interested on developing software since the age of 15.

I specialize in web ui, desktop, mobile and back-end development with Java. I believe that I am also experienced in many other technologies, dev-ops and leading the development life cycle. I put emphasis on developing clean, efficient software, design patterns and perspectives (IOC, DI, TDD, AOP, OOP, BDD, Reactive Manifesto, Scrum & XP & Agile, Pair etc.).

I want to create added value for the world of software development industry and produce new technologies.

I believe that the years are not important nevertheless my total working experience of development is almost for **9 years**.(On present 72 month full-time + 15 month internship + 18 month freelance)

My native language is Turkish and i am mid-level on daily and technical conversations in English. I have **type-b** driver license. My military service is done. My hobbies are reading articles about any topic of the science, theology, philosophy, politics and also playing chess and video games, listening and singing, coding on OSS.

WORKING AREAS

- **ERP** applications
- Distributed application design
- RPC, SOAP and RESTful Web Services
- Microservices
- Android Client Apps
- SQL optimization
- Copy Routine, data structure generation
- Report Generation
- Software safety, licensing and obfuscation
- Preparing software design documentations
- Performance analysis / metrics
- Integration, overload, penetration testing

- Responsive UI Design
- Socket Programming
- Content Robots (Crawlers)
- Reverse Engineering
- PHP compiling (HHVM)
- Online Game scripting and management
- Big Data / Cloud
- **Issue Tracking Systems**
- Search Engine Optimization
- Machine learning
- CMS(WP,Vbulletin etc.) programming
- Smart Home Systems / IoT

EDUCATION

SAKARYA UNIVERSITY Faculty Of Technology

2010 - 2014 SauSensor - For control of the Wireless Sensor Networks improve business SAKARYA/TURKEY intelligence structure with Restful Web Services

> Used Spring ROO, Maven, Heroku, Log4j, Spring Core, Spring Security, Spring For Android, Spring MVC, JPA&Hibernate, AspectJ, PostgreSQL, Cordova etc.

SauRSSI - Positioning with trilateration and path loss methods on Android Platforms

Used Android API

TraviNeural - Online game strategy and auto-pilot application with artificial neural networks.

Used PHP, CURL Library, ANN Algorithms

Eit - A basic issue tracking system like mantisbt.

- Used Spring ROO, Maven, Heroku, Log4j, Spring Core, Spring
- Security, Spring For Android, Spring MVC, FlexJson,
- JPA&Hibernate, AspectJ, MYSQL etc.

AKHISAR ANADOLU TEKNIK LISESI Computing Division

MANISA/TURKEY 2006 - 2010 Web/Multimedia Management and Webmaster

Last update : 01/2021

WORK EXPERIENCE

YAŞAR BİLGİ IŞLEM VE TICARET A.Ş. (ASTRON)

eng.yasarbilgi.com.tr

Software Specialist

08.2017 - PRESENT Dijital.Sirket - An ERP software. I develop on SAP BW integration, bi, reports, iZMiR/TURKEY performance analysis

> Used: Spring, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Liquibase, Apache Camel, ActiveMQ **Dijital.Printer & Document Template Editor -** Desktop and web application **PSU & YBP Integration** - Integration web applications for companies **Production Node Editor (Bill Of Materials) -** Vue UI application and java back-end for creating Bill of Materials data.

Dijital.Integration - Vue material design and Java LDAP & Mail integration services.

Used: Spring Boot, Spring Cloud Stack, Keycloak, Vu.

Dijital.Form - Form builder application for creating auto-generated communication forms with metadata.

Dijital.Izleme - Application for monitoring web application performance and metrics.

CONTROL 4 OTOMASYON TEKNOLOJILERI SAN. TIC. LTD. ŞTI İZMİR 07.2014− 10.2016 (FULL TIME) iZMiR/TURKEY control4.com

Full Stack Software Engineer

Maar Project

In short, Maar Project is an iot system for intelligent home management. I took place in the section of Project management analysis equipment, android, desktop and server-side software development.

More info at: http://www.maar.com.tr

Briefly developed sub-projects;

Maar Box - MaarBox is the android endpoint in the houses and perform home management.

Using Android APIs of GPIO, RS485, USB and TCP protocols for the management of industrial and household equipment was made.

Used: Gradle, multi productFlavors, native libs, androidannotations, androidannotations-ormlite, ormlite-api, zxing, jpa, apache mina, bcprov, jsoup, csipsimple, crosswalk webview

Maar Mobile (IOS and Android) - It is a mobile software for remote home management. I took part in the android section of the project.

Used: Gradle, multi productFlavors, native libs, androidannotations, ormlite-api, zxing, jpa, apache mina, bcprov, spring-android-rest-template

Maar Server - Software of data communication required for remote home management (MQ structure we have developed our own) and makes data management.

Used: Maven, spring roo, thymeleaf, slf4i, jackson-lib, apache commons, mysql, hibernate, jpa, hibernate-validation, jsr303, spring-transactions, spring-security, apache mina, spring mvc, spring-websocket, spring boot, bcprov, spring data

Maar Project Builder - UI and data structure generator software of MaarBox and MaarMobile.

Used: Maven, slf4j, spring boot, java-fx, jpa, jackson-lib, hibernate, h2 db, mysql, hsqldb, json-io, gson, spring data

Magic Buttons Project - Android and desktop software that can communicate directly with Control4 devices.

Magic Buttons Android

Used: Gradle, commons, json-io, apache mina, grid-layout Magic Buttons UI Builder - UI and data structure generator desktop software of Magic Buttons android app.

Used: Maven, spring data, h2 db, jpa, hibernate, jackson-lib, gson, json-io, xstream, imgscalr, yamlbeans, msgpack, protobuf, protostuff, java-fx

Last update : 01/2021

Siparişlerim Project

A Digital concierge service.

More info at: https://siparislerim.com

Siparişlerim Android Application

Used: Gradle, multi productFlavors, crosswalk webview, gcm. **RestMail Web Application - Simple RESTful mail sending service.**

Used: Maven, javax.mail, spring-boot, spring mvc.

GcmServer Web Application - Simple RESTful gcm notification service.

Used: maven, spring roo, jetty, mysql, commons, jsr-303, hibernate-validation, slf4j, spring data, spring mvc, apache tiles, jackson-lib, jpa

ARVENA AKıllı İŞ ÇÖZÜMLERI Java Software Developer

07.2013 - 01.2014 (INTERNSHIP) & 01.2014-06.2014 (PART-TIME) SAKARYA/TURKEY arvena.com.tr

SmartBase - Enterprise Android Framework

- Form Builder
- Easy Data Binding, Active Record
- Easy Logging, Theme Support, Telephony Managers UI Components
- Web Service Providers etc.

Arvena Store - Android-Based Inventory and Work Order Management System

Mikro ERP Integration with .Net Web Services

Arvena Business - Operation Confirmation Application for Android

Axapta (Microsoft Dynamics AX) Integration with .Net Web Services

Arvena Anket - Survey Application for Android

Used SmartBase Form Builder

Arvena Gallery - Customizable gallery application for Android MKSMontaj - Operation Confirmation Application for Android

- Mikro ERP Integration with .Net Web Services
- Used SmartBase Enterprise Android Framework

ARMAP - Customer Positioning & Salesman Control Application for Android

- Arvena Salesman Integration
- Used Google Maps API

DTS TEKNOLOJI AR-GE YAZıLıM EĞITIM VE DANIŞMANLIK 07.2012 - 01.2013 (INTERNSHIP)

.Net Software Developer

Created apps for automate Preprocessing of Particle Simulation 3d Modelling with SolidWorks API, OpenCascade and QT.

FREELANCE | Search Engine Optimization (SEO) Specialist

05.2010-11.2011 REMOTE

SAKARYA/TURKEY

Development of more than 150 websites which includes SEO tasks was completed. SEO and SEM softwares were developed with php.

GÜRKOM İLETIŞIM BILGI İŞLEM VE GÜVENLIK LTD.ŞTI 04.2008 - 09.2008 (INTERNSHIP) Web site development MANISA/TURKEY

Web Development Assistant

TECHNOLOGIES

DevOps

- Sonatype
- Jenkins
- GitLab
- Bash scripting & Deployment processes
- Graylog
- Grafana, prometheus, Graphite
- Docker and kubernetes (only dev. env.)

Documentation

- xwiki
- gitlab/github
- ms office
- swagger

Platforms

- JIRA
- Heroku
- MantisBT
- Bitbucket
- Github

Tools

- Apache Maven
- Docker Compose
- Gradle
- Npm
- Svn
- Git
- Tomcat
- Jetty
- HHVM
- Jitpack
- Postman
- SOAPUI
- Vsphere Client and Virtual Box,VNC

Testing

- Selenium
- TestContainers

IDE

- IntelliJ IDEA & PhpStorm
- MS Visual Studio
- vscode
- Netbeans
- Eclipse & Eclipse MemoryAnalyzer
- DBeaver
- OllyDbg
- Adobe Fireworks & Flash
- Adobe Photoshop
- SolidWorks API

Backend

- Java
- Android API
 - WebRtc Client
 - Android Annotations Lib
 - Dagger
 - RabbitMQ
 - Modbus,GPIO,rs485,usb (Industrial devices)
 - knx calimero
 - libylc
 - Crosswalk Webview
 - Spring For Android
 - Csipsimple
 - Libvlc
 - Jsoup, zxing, bcprov, imgscalr
- Spring Framework
- Spring Microservices
- Spring Boot
- Spring Core
- Spring Data & Transactions
- Spring Data R2DBC
- Spring MVC & Mobile & RESTful Web Services
- Spring Reactive Stack
- Spring Retry
- Spring Circuit Breaker
- Spring Config Server
- Spring Vault
- Spring Security
- Spring For Android
- Spring ROO
- Spring Web Flow
- Vertx (Reactive discipline and networking)
- Apache Camel
- J2SE,J2ME,JMS
- AspectJ
- WebSocket
- Net Framework
- Yii Framework
- A bit of Objective C and dev. env.

Security

- Keycloak
- OWASP tools (ZAP etc.)

Persistence

- Data warehouse knowage
- Materialized Views
- Streaming data analysis
- Hazelcast
- Liquibase
- Elide & GraphQL
- ElasticSearch
- ORMLite
- JPA & Hibernate
- Postgres, MYSQL, H2Db, MSSQL, SQLite
- Jackson Mapping, json-io, JAXB, xstream, yamlbeans, msgpack
- MongoDB with Spring ROO
- Protocol Buffers, protostuff
- HikariCP

Presentation

- Jauery
- Vue.js
- d3.js, tabulator etc.
- Dev Express (.net only)
- Swagger
- Grafana
- Thymeleaf
- JSF (PrimeFaces)
- Twitter Bootstrap
- Apache Tiles
- Freemarker
- Jasper Reports
- Java FX 2
- JOGI
- WPF/Silverlight
- OT

Learning and interested on:

Native Cloud, GraalVM, loadbalancers and service discovery (kubernetes, nginx, zuul, eureka), distributed transactions, AWS, Akka, Redis, jhipster, CQRS, fabric8, karaf, portlet, Apache spark, istio, graalvm, quarkus, cuba-platform, kotlin, flutter & dart lang, Cucumber, buck.

My OSS

- Fluent Querv
- Apache-Mina-Builder
- (I working on a js library in these times)

Please look over my github stars for what i'm interested on now. aithub.com/firatgursoy?tab=stars

Peace.